PRATIKSHA KARN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

04 5171 1849 | karnprtksh11@gmail.com | Lakemba, NSW| LinkedIn.com/in/pratiksha-karn-9139a921a

SUMMARY

Energetic, forward-looking software developer with experience in designing and developing websites and graphics design dedicated to improving skills through hands-on learning and development work. Committed at using HTML5, JavaScript and other programming languages to produce clean code. Well-organized and collaborative team player with strong communication and analytical abilities. Enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript Programming
- React JS, Node.js, HTML, CSS
- SQL Server, Mysql, postgresql, MongoDB
- Nginx, Docker, GitLab, AWS, CI/CD
- Code Debugging
- Technical Writing
- Wordpress
- Practical knowledge of SQL and database concepts
- Adobe AI/PS/XD
- Content Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Dzango Tech Accelerator | Hong Kong (remote) | Feb 2022 – Aug 2022

- Worked with back-end developers to design APIs.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and JSON coding.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems, and corrected issues.
- Developed unit test cases for testing and automation.
- Demonstrated a high level of initiative and creativity while tackling difficult tasks.
- Learned and adapted quickly to new technology and software applications.
- Developed strong organizational and communication skills through coursework.
- Organized and detail-oriented with a strong work ethic.
- Strengthened communication skills through regular interactions with others.
- Worked well in a team setting, providing support and guidance.

React JS Developer

Code Karkhana | Kathmandu, Nepal | Jul 2021 – Feb 2022

- Developed user-friendly web forms with validation and error handling.
- Worked with senior developers and designers to implement sofwares using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.
- Built front-end web Interface for engineers to control and monitor onboard system that visualized perceived surroundings and set routes of autonomous driving system.

Graphic Designer and Wordpress Developer

Freelance | Nepal | 2019-Present

- Met with customers to present mockups and collect information for adjustments.
- Developed print materials such as brochures, banners and signs.
- Used Adobe softwares to create images and layouts.
- Contributed design ideas in early planning stages with customers and project managers.
- Developed creative design for print materials, banners and signs.
- Developed graphics and visual content for social media campaigns.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Electronics & Communication Engineering

Kathford Int'l College, Tribhuvan University, Nepal

Percentage: 71.24

Master of Information Technology

University of New Castle, Sydney, New South Wales

Jan 2023 - Present

LANGUAGE

English, Nepali, Hindi

RESEARCH

Smart Wheelchair with SMS Alert and Safety Features, Research Paper

June 2021

https://www.researchgate.net/publication/352707347_Smart_Wheelchair_with_SMS_Alert_and_Safety_Features

Automatic Cattle Feeding System, Research Paper

Sept 2019

https://www.researchgate.net/publication/337159115_Automatic_Cattle_Feeding_System

COURSES AND TRAINING

Introduction to Data Science

Jul 2020

 $Cognitive \ Class, \ \underline{https://courses.cognitiveclass.ai/certificates/88d28414f8a44ad9b6c74c46094c797b}$

Data Science Methodology

July 2020

Cognitive Class, https://courses.cognitiveclass.ai/certificates/f8ac8ced904046f6b5f9ba342ea1079f

Participant in the training on Empowering Women in Geospatial Information Technology

EXTRA

Participant in Webinar on Internet of Things System

Aug 2020

IEEE Nepal Sub-section

Volunteer in Kathfest Kathford Int'l College, Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal Jan 2019

ICIMOD, Kathmandu, Nepal

June 2018

Participation in 16th National Technological Festival IOE, Pulchowk Campus, Kathmandu, Nepal

2019